cmscritic.com 2019-07-23

# Privacy Policy and Data Protection - CMS Critic

Here at CMS Critic we value and protect your privacy

This policy explains when and why we collect information about you, how we use it, the conditions under which we may disclose it to others and how we keep it secure.

We may change this Policy from time to time so please check this page occasionally to ensure that you’re happy with any changes. By using our website, you’re agreeing to be bound by this Policy.

Any questions regarding this Policy and our privacy practices should be sent by email to [[email protected]](https://www.cmscritic.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

## Who are we?

CMS Critic is an online blog founded in 2008 by Mike Johnston. We share articles and editorials as well as other blog content. We are based in Canada but have contributing authors from around the world.

## How we Collect Information About You

Information is collected via log files, cookies, leaving comments on the site or subscribing to our newsletter.

## What Information do we Collect About You

We collect information on your name, email address, website (if you leave this in a comment), IP address and the pages that you visited and when you visited them on the site.

Any financial details are collected via PayPal which does not retain any financial information once the transaction has been processed.

## How and Why we Track your Visit

Like most websites around the world we use Google [Analytics](https://www.cmscritic.com/clicky "Web Analytics in Real Time | Clicky") (GA) to process information about the number of visitors on our site, and their behavior

We use this information to record the number of people using CMS Critic and to better understand where you discover our site (from social media, google or another site) and how you use it as well as to see how people move throughout the site.

GA records your approximate location down to town level, the type device you are using e.g. Mobile or Table, Name of device e.g. iPad, iPhone etc…, operating system e.g. Windows 10 or iOS and browser e.g. Firefox or Chrome none of this data can be used to identify you.

Google does record your IP address however, we don't have access to this information and it modifies it so that you can not be identified specifically just the area that you are in.

### Google Analytics Demographics

We are committed to ensuring that our website contains content that is valuable and useful to our readers.

To help us with this we have implemented the Google [analytics](https://www.cmscritic.com/clicky "Web Analytics in Real Time | Clicky") demographics and interest reporting features on our website.

These tools allow us to review anonymous data regarding the gender, age and interests of website visitors and adapt our website content to better reflect their needs.

Although this information is collected through your Google ad settings, it is not provided to us in a personally-identifiable format. This means we cannot identify what information is about you, and we will not try to figure it out.

You can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customise Google Display Network ads using the [Google Ad settings](https://adssettings.google.ca/anonymous?sig=ACi0TCim925cB07-7cpwU1t82Zih-cyZJ-z258Rhs2_ob_VD9-KN0PF7SNjosxPqWAnMkL5o3KkIzcaiKhInpLNrtrjGb3FOZ2AF3COImtlEVfU_oOnno0I&hl=en) or through the [Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

To do this Google Analytics uses a “cookie” on your machine read more about Cookies below.

## Leaving a Comment on our Site

Here are CMS Critic we love hearing from you and we do this by giving you the option of leaving a comment.

To leave a comment you can use our commenting platform, Disqus. You can read their privacy policy [here](https://help.disqus.com/terms-and-policies/disqus-privacy-policy).

We only use this information to identify you as the comment maker and do not pass this on to any third party.

Your email address will never be shown in the comment section of the site.

Your details will remain in the database unless we remove it or the article is removed from the site.

You may request that we delete the comment and remove you details at any time. Please email us at [[email protected]](https://www.cmscritic.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) to ask for this to be carried out.

If you are under 16 you must obtain your parents permission before leaving a comment.

**IMPORTANT: In your comment you should avoid leaving information of a personal nature and it is recommended that you do this on any website you comment on.**

## Subscriber Newsletter

If you choose to join one of our regular newsletters then your email address is required so that you can be sent the emails.

Your data is collected and then passed to our Email Service Provider, Mail Chimp.[  
](https://www.activecampaign.com/)

You may unsubscribe at any time from our newsletters using the unsubscribe link at the bottom of the email or you can email us and ask that you be removed. _Please make sure that you are using the same email address as you receive the emails from to do this._

Within the Email Service Provider we use tags to track the pages that you visit and actions that you take within the emails so that we can provide a more personalized email service to you.

We may send emails 1 – 3 times a week and with our tracking try and make these as relevant to you as possible. From time to time we may include promotions for products.

## Advertisements on CMS Critic

We use third party advertisements on CMS Critic to support our site.

  * Google Double Click
  * Affiliate Links
  * Direct Advertising

Some of these advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our site, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdSense program) information including your IP address, your ISP , the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed.

This is generally used for geotargeting purposes (showing New York real estate ads to someone in New York, for example) or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited (such as showing cooking ads to someone who frequents cooking sites).

## Cookies

Cookies are pieces of code that we use to track your use of our site and provide the best possible experience for you.

Specifically we use them for

  * Our commenting system so that you don’t have to always enter you details
  * Collect data as part of Google Analytics so that we can see who has visited our website

You can chose to disable or selectively turn off our cookies or third-party cookies in your browser settings, or by managing preferences in your browser.

However, this can affect how you are able to interact with our site as well as other websites. This could include the inability to login to services or programs, such as logging into forums or accounts.

  * Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on  cmscritic.com
  * Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to cmscritic.com and other sites on the Internet.
  * You may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL – <https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads>

## If you are Under 16

Please obtain your parents permission before entering any personal information on our website, we are concerned with your privacy as much as an adults.

## When we may Transfer your Personal Data

We will not transfer your personal data unless we are under legal obligation to do so.

## If you wish to be Removed from our Data

At any point you may ask that we remove your information from our systems. Please contact us with your requirements and we will do so within a month.

The same applies for what information we hold about you and can be identified as being about you.
